<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DudeWhoCode</title>
    <link>http://dudewho.codes/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DudeWhoCode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 08:40:28 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://dudewho.codes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building better python microservices with grpc</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/talks/grpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 08:38:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/talks/grpc/</guid>
      <description>Today, massive systems are running on microservices communicating with each other using REST APIs. HTTP is easy to get started, loosely structured and does good job in exchanging messages. But it&amp;rsquo;s convenience comes with a performance trade-off, which takes us back to other optimal alternative: gRPC
Video
Slides
Events: Pycon Malaysia 2018, Pycon India 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paraview Session Manager</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/pvsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/pvsession/</guid>
      <description>Featured Skills: Golang, Docker, Caddy Web Server, WebSockets, Azure Cloud Company: TarkaLabs
One of the products of a client is used by mining industry to visualize what is under the mountain before starting the actual mining. This will help miners to decide on the equipments and dynamites. I built the backend to support the visualization tool that spins off docker containers on demand with custom mount points from azure blob storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy maketh an Engineer</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/talks/empathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/talks/empathy/</guid>
      <description>The journey towards becoming a better developer involves in more than just coding. Empathy is the most important skill that any developer should practice. In this talk we will see as a developer how to write code empathetically and how empathy will help you to become a better software craftsman. By the end of the talk, audience will know how to practice empathy, build great softwares and great teams empathetically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vue Studio</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/vuestudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/vuestudio/</guid>
      <description>Featured Skills: Python3, Django, Serverless, AWS ECS, lambda, Athena, Transcoder, Docker I worked on this when I was a product engineer at MadStreetDen.
Vue Studio is an A.I powered video marketing tool that helps the customer to monetize their video assets. It enables the purchase of the fashion items appearing on the video, directly form the video player. I worked closely with the frontend and product design team in architecting and developing an highly scalable backend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backend Army</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/backendarmy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/backendarmy/</guid>
      <description>I am currently side hustling with Backend Army. It is premium hands on courses to scale one&amp;rsquo;s backend skills. I am trying to bridge the gap between learning backend engineering by shipping to production and hands on video courses. You can checkout the publication here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurrency vs Parallelism</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/talks/concurrency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/talks/concurrency/</guid>
      <description>A good code is one which uses the system resources efficiently which means not over utilizing the resources as well as not under utilizing by leaving them idle. One of the main features of Python3 is its asynchronous capabilities. After getting to know what is concurrency and why concurrency is not parallelism. We will see how can we leverage the asyncio library&amp;rsquo;s functionalities to design and run our code concurrently, use our resources efficiently and finish the tasks blazingly fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IOT meets Serverless</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/talks/iot_serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 08:35:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/talks/iot_serverless/</guid>
      <description>Speed and agility are the most expected in today’s analytics tools. The quicker you get from idea to insights, the more you can innovate &amp;amp; perform ad-hoc data analysis. I will be talking about how we can use AWS serverless architecture to stream IoT data, managed by python. We can be up and running in minutes―starting small, but able to easily grow to millions of devices and billions of messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAD stack</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/madstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/madstack/</guid>
      <description>Featured Skills: Python, Golang, PostgreSQL, Django, MicroServices, AWS, Docker Company: MadStreetDen
One of the core engineer who helped in abstracting a large, monolithic A.I platform into microservices architecture. This paved the way for MadStreetDen to build a full scale e-commerce suite of products: vue commerce. This platform sits as a base for most of the A.I products coming out of the company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and Scaling a serverless logging platform</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/talks/serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 23:25:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/talks/serverless/</guid>
      <description>Serverless architectures has been around for past few years and there has been quite a few skepticism surrounding it. Few might argue that it’s just another buzzword for marketing. But serverless architectures offer more than a catchy buzzword. In this talk we will discuss, what is serverless, when to and when not to use them and how can we use Amazon Web Services to implement a real-time, production grade serverless logging pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Logging framework</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/serverless/</guid>
      <description>Featured Skills: Python, OOP, AWS Lambda, AWS Athena, AWS Kinesis, AWS quicksight, AWS s3, Redis Company: MadStreetDen
Implemented a logging client with OOP paradigms in mind. The object oriented approach helped in distributing the ownership of data integrity among all owners of the microservices where logging client is used. I also implemented a serverless backend for this logging framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write code for humans, not machines</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/talks/code_for_humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 08:38:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/talks/code_for_humans/</guid>
      <description>Any average programmer can write code by sitting hours and hours, pushing themselves through the sleepless nights but what it takes to write a better readable code?Forget about the design patterns, I will be talking ground zero from naming variables to handling errors in your python code. After the talk the audience will know how to get started with good programming habits and how not to annoy the code readers:)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RESTful DB</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/restful-db/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/restful-db/</guid>
      <description>Featured Skills: Python, Django, Postgresql, Psycopg2, ORM, uWSGI Company: MadStreetDen
Developed a REST API driven microservice around PostgreSQL database. This helped in rapid iterations of schema changes. Even though there were multiple microservices using the database, only this microservice had to be touched in case of schema change. Was able to derive more insights about slow queries and traffic patterns that affects the DataBase in API layer itself. API versioning helped in canary deployment for new schema roll outs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t just stop with your Fibonacci code</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/talks/fibonacci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 08:40:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/talks/fibonacci/</guid>
      <description>A fun and meme filled lightning talk for university students on whats waiting for them in the software world out there and how to stand out in the crowd.
Slides
Events: MuPy 2017, Manipal University</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Message Routing MicroService</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/message-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/message-router/</guid>
      <description> Featured Skills: Python, Multi-threading, Concurrency Company: MadStreetDen
 Built an I/O heavy, multi-tenant microservice that sits in ingestion part of the pipeline. This routes the data (products from the catalog) to different microservices and scales horizontally. Used multi threading to achieve the throughput of 10K messages per minute.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingestion MicroService</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/ingestion-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/ingestion-service/</guid>
      <description> Featured Skills: Python, Multi-threading, Multi-processing Company: MadStreetDen
 Developed a framework to ingest and parse product catalogs from various sources like HTTP, FTP, AWS SQS, S3. Implemented in a Object Oriented way which helped in writing custom parser for different e-commerce clients.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devops Culturalist</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/devops-culturalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/devops-culturalist/</guid>
      <description>Featured Skills: Devops cycle, Ansible, CircleCI, Docker, Convincing People:) Company: TarkaLabs
Not a project per se, but a fancy name init?
I was pushing devops practices into the team for which I consulted for: DataCloud. I started it by giving a talk on what devops is, then setting up basic git practices, branch ethics, test cases and finally CI/CD systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decahose Data Management Platform</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/ddmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/ddmp/</guid>
      <description> Featured Skills: Python, Apache Kafka, Storm, Cassandra, ElasticSearch Company: Serendio
 Architected and developed a real-time data pipeline. This pipeline ingests high volume of twitter stream, extract information on the fly using NLP and expose the stored data via REST API. This pipeline was deployed in bare metal servers.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emoto Data</title>
      <link>http://dudewho.codes/projects/emoto-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dudewho.codes/projects/emoto-data/</guid>
      <description> Featured Skills: Python, Kafka, Cassandra, ElasticSearch Company: Serendio
 Developed an architecture to handle streaming data from Chinese websites. This service streams data from various Chinese websites like sina weibo, tencent, renren, etc. enriches it on the fly and stores them.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>